- Ibrahim X : @sle1i
In the beginning, there
was only the ocean.
Until she emerged, our
mother island, Te Fiti.
Her heart held the power
to create life itself.
And Te Fiti shared
it with the world.
Over time, some tried to claim
the heart for themselves.
For they believed that
if they could possess
it, the power of
creation would be theirs.
And one day, the boldest of them all
dared to cross the vast ocean to take it.
He was a demigod of
the wind and sea.
A warrior.
A trickster.
A shapeshifter.
Who could change his form with
the power of his magical fishhook.
And his name was Maui.
It was already rumbling before
we arrived here, wasn't it?
It began to rumble.
The birth of a
terrible darkness.
Now he tried to flee.
But then he encountered another
who had their eyes on the heart.
Te Ka.
A demon of earth and fire.
Now his power waned.
Never seen again.
And his magical fishhook
and the heart of Te Fiti
were lost in the sea.
Where even now, a thousand
years later, Te Ka and the
demons of the deep are still
searching for the heart.
Hidden in a darkness that
will flare up again and again.
They are sucking the life
out of island after island.
Until we are all devoured by the
bloodthirsty, inescapable claws of death.
But one day, the
heart will be found.
By someone.
Who will undertake the
journey beyond our reef?
Find Maui.
Bring him across
the great ocean.
To return the heart of Te Fiti.
And save us all.
Amen.
Whoops, whoops, whoops, whoops.
Thank you, Mother.
Dad.
There she is.
As you all know, no one
ventures beyond the reef.
We are safe here.
There is no darkness.
And there are no monsters.
There are no monsters.
As long as we stay on our safe
island, everything will be fine.
The legends are true, my son.
Don't worry, I'll help you.
Shh!
Leave it alone!
Do you want to see the ocean?
Yes, me too.
Wow!
Moana!
Moana, don't go out
there, it's dangerous.
Moana, listen, beyond the reef there
is nothing but storms and rough seas.
Moana!
That's my little adventurer.
You are very important, darling, and
the next great leader of our people.
And you will do
wonderful things.
Can I do them in the water?
No.
Never pass the reef.
Come.
The first thing you should do
is find out where you belong.
Moana, make way, make way,
for the end of the time you
know is the village of
Motunui, which is all you need.
The dance floor is practicing,
the girls are singing
ancient songs, we have to
stop, but I need it so much.
The street, the toilet is
broken, the shin and Moana,
there is so much to do,
the truth in the tarot.
That is all you need.
We share everything we
make, we joke and weave
our baskets, the fishermen
return from the sea.
Now we are no longer seen.
Don't go away, stand still, now our
people need a trick, but there you are.
Now comes the dance,
and you will look around
and realize that happiness
is where you are.
Look at the coconut, look
at its trees, use every
single coconut location,
that is all we need.
From the fibers we make our
nets, the water inside is sweet,
we use the leaves to make fire
and to hide blood and needles.
If you look at the
coconut, the trees, the
leaves, the island gives
us everything we need.
And don't worry.
Let's run away from lingering,
we are safe and well provided
for, and when we look into
the future, there you are.
She will be fine.
When you live right next to it, you have
to find happiness exactly where you are.
I like to dance with the water,
the undercurrent, and the wings.
The water is mysterious.
I like how it
behaves next to it.
Some people might think I'm crazy
or say that I drift too far.
But once you know what you
like, you're just in it.
You are truly your father's
daughter: stubbornness and pride.
Listen to what he says, but don't forget:
you could also hear an inner voice.
And when that voice begins to
whisper, follow the father's star.
Go ahead, that inner
voice is who you are.
Moana.
Dad, I wasn't planning
on going out there.
I'm just conducting my
daily canoe inspection.
Join me.
I've wanted to bring you here since
the moment you opened your eyes.
This is a sacred place.
A place of chiefs.
Soon you will come of age.
And bring a stone to this
mountain, just as I did.
Just as my father did.
And his mother did.
And every single
chief who ever was.
And the day you bring
your stone there,
you will lift the
whole island higher.
You are the future
of our people, Moana.
And our people
are not out there.
They are right here.
It's time to prepare to
be the person they need.
So here I stay.
All my life, people around me
And when I think of tomorrow
Where we are
I will leave
I will have my
people to guide me.
We will build our
future together.
Where we are
Where you are
You can find happiness, right
Stay here.
Thank you very much.
We need to check the
meaning of the word "stay".
Over there.
It's getting worse.
People leader.
It's important, Pua.
It's forever.
What's wrong?
It's not just about
the coconuts anymore.
It's terrible for the catch.
We've explored
the entire lagoon.
But no fish.
They just...
...disappeared.
Do you remember
when my grandmother
was the leader?
A hurricane washed the
fish away for weeks.
But they had stored dried fish
and fresh coconuts.
We were ready to wait
until the fish came back.
And he came back.
There is no hurricane.
And even then,
the lagoons never empty.
There is always a solution,
you just have to look for it.
Which one?
If the lagoon is empty, what if we
fish further out? Beyond the reef.
No one ventures beyond the reef.
But we can't rely on coconuts.
And the fish here are gone.
Moana.
We have a rule.
A rule will never feed us.
A rule protects us.
We have to do something.
Moana.
I didn't say we should go beyond the
reef because I want to be on the ocean.
I know.
But somehow, yes.
I'm trying to be
what our people need.
What he needs.
But that doesn't seem
to be enough for him.
He was just like you, Moana.
Dad.
Drawn to the sea.
Ignored the warning:
Don't cross the reef.
He took a canoe
and passed the reef into the
unpredictable ocean. Waves like mountains.
Sometimes the question
of who we would like
to be and who we must
be doesn't match up.
As long as I can remember,
I never really knew what
I wished to be, to play
the perfect daughter.
But I keep returning
to the water.
No matter how hard I try,
every time I take every path,
every way I follow that I go,
every path leads back
to the place I know.
Where I cannot go, where
I would love to be.
Look at the line in the sky.
I have to look at it closely.
And no one knows
how far it goes.
When the wind in my sail
stays on the sea behind me.
What they all know.
When I go, it's completely
unclear how far I will go.
I know everyone on this island.
They seem so happy
on this island.
Everything is planned.
I know everyone on this island.
They have a goal on this island.
Maybe I can continue
with mine then.
I can lead with pride.
I can make us strong.
I am content when I play along.
But the inner voice
sings a different song.
What's wrong with me?
Let's keep a light
burning at this time.
Come and see.
What are you doing?
No one knows
No one knows.
How difficult.
And it seems like it's
falling out of me.
So come and find me.
And let me know.
But beyond this line.
When I cross this line.
The line overlooking the sea.
And it calls me.
And don't want to.
I am quite a redhead though.
When I feel the wind in my
sails, the sea stays behind me.
One day I will know.
How far I will go.
It's okay.
We are fine.
I can do this.
There are more fish.
Not bad.
Hold on.
Wow, let's see.
I don't have to
tell him anything.
He was right.
I don't belong out there.
I have to bring my
stone to the mountain.
Okay.
Have fun.
You're not going
to try and stop me?
You said it was what you wanted.
Yes.
When I die, I will be
reborn as one of these.
Oh, I chose the wrong tattoo.
Why are you acting so strange?
I'm the village crazy person,
that's my job. So come
on, if you want to tell me
something, just tell me.
Is there something you want to tell me?
Is there something you want to hear?
Has this mountain gotten higher?
You have been told all
the stories of our people,
except one.
What is this place?
Do you really think our
ancestors stayed within the reef?
What's in there?
The answer to the question
you keep asking yourself.
Go inside.
Beat the drum.
And find out.
Who should I be?
Beat the drum.
We were seafarers?
We were seafarers!
Grandma!
I have many questions!
Why did we stop?
When he stole the heart of Te
Fiti and evil took its course,
Te Ka awoke, monsters appeared
and the canoes never returned.
To protect our people, the old chiefs,
for so long, we forgot who we are.
And now the darkness has
finally caught up with us.
It's everywhere.
The island is dying.
The stories are true.
The story has just begun.
I saw you that day, Moana.
In the water.
I thought it was a dream.
The ocean chose you to
travel beyond our reef.
Find Maui.
Bring him across the great ocean so
he can restore the heart of Te Fiti.
And save us all.
Our ancestors believed that Maui is
down there lying on his fishhook.
Follow the path, and
you will find him.
Dad must know.
I will show him the canoes.
He will help.
Do what you have
to do, but hurry.
Hurry.
I know how we can fix this.
We can find Maui.
I have the heart.
If we follow the stars, the
hook, then we see canoes.
Dad, we were once seafarers.
We can go to sea again.
Do you think you are the first
one Grandma took to this place?
You knew that?
Our ancestors didn't close
their cave for no reason.
They were trying to protect us.
No, Dad!
You told me to help our people.
Ignoring who we are
doesn't help our people.
We have to find Maui and
bring back the heart.
Our island is dying.
We cannot stand by and watch.
That is nothing at all.
Chief!
Your mother!
Go.
Not again.
You must.
The ocean chose you.
Follow the fishhook.
And when you've found Maui, you grab him
by the ear and say: I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat, sail across the
sea, and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
I cannot leave you.
There is no place you could
go where I won't be with you.
Go.
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat,
sail out to sea, and restore
the heart of Te Fiti.
Hei, Hei!
See? See, everything is fine.
Look, the ocean is my friend.
Hei, Hei.
Please tell me you
brought your own food.
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat,
sail out to sea, and restore
the heart of Te Fiti.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no. No, no, no.
Oh come on, no, no.
Come.
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat.
I am Moana.
Moana! Please help me!
Um, what? I asked for help. And this?
My boat destroyed? That doesn't help me!
Fish pee on you! All day long!
And much worse things, so...
Maui?
Maui!
I am Moana of Motunui.
You will board my boat,
sail out to sea, and restore
the heart of Te Fiti.
You're getting in now...
You will board my boat. Yes!
You will board my...
Boat!
God gave me a boat!
You can take the
little human back!
Oh, I'm going to eat it.
It's a chicken! His
name is Hei Hei.
His name is Yum-Yum. When
he goes into my belly.
Maui! Mhm!
Shape-shifter!
Mm-hmm!
Demigod of the wind and sea.
Yes!
I am Moana of...
Whoops, whoops, whoops, whoops.
Hero of men.
Huh?
It goes like this.
Maui, shape-shifter, demigod of
the wind and sea, hero of men.
Oh, the women.
Women too.
Men and women.
This isn't a thing
between girls and boys.
Men and women.
Maui is a hero for everyone.
I think you're doing great.
Start at the very top.
Three, two, one.
Go for it!
I am Moana...
I am...
No, no, you're
completely overwhelmed.
But don't worry.
Maui always has
time for his fans.
Oh, I'm not a..
That's fine.
May I see the orb?
Thank you.
All right.
You know, before I sign anything, I'd
like to learn something about you.
Tell me about your hopes.
Tell me about your dreams.
Well, I think I've sort of...
Time is up.
I had to pass.
Two, one.
Find out what you dream,
and follow those dreams.
Oh, the chicken
just pecked my foot.
Oh, the chicken.
Autograph.
For the chicken.
Look at that face.
I know, you don't get the opportunity
to see your hero every day.
You are not my hero.
And I'm not here for
you to sign my orb.
I'm here because you stole...
That.
The heart of Te Fiti.
And you will board my boat, sail
across the sea, and bring it back.
You know, it's kind of
crazy because it almost
sounds like you don't like
me, which is impossible.
Because look at me.
I've been stranded on this
island for over a thousand years
because I tried to get this
heart as a gift for you mortals.
So I think what you're trying
to say is: I appreciate you.
What?
I'm grateful to you.
Huh?
That's fine.
I won't tease you anymore.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
No, no.
I didn't...
I didn't say...
Thank you.
Okay, okay.
I see what's going on, yes.
You're facing authority
and it's strange.
You don't even
know how you feel.
It's adorable.
Oh, good to see that
people never change.
Open your eyes.
Let's begin.
Yes, that's really true.
Maui.
Breathe it in.
I know, it's a lot.
The hair.
The body.
When you're staring
at a demigod.
What can I say,
except: You're welcome.
For the tides, the sun, the sky.
Hey, it's all good,
it's all good.
You're welcome.
I'm just an ordinary demigod.
Hey, what has two thumbs
and holds up the sky?
While you were waddling up
there, this guy was cheering.
When the nights got cold, who
stole the fire from below for you?
You're looking at him, man.
Oh.
Also, I lassoed the sun.
You're welcome.
To lengthen your days
and bring you joy.
I also use the breeze.
You're welcome.
To strengthen your nails and
make your dreams come true.
What more can I say,
except: You're welcome.
For the islands, I
drop from the sea.
There's no need to
pray until the day.
You're welcome.
Ha!
I think that's just my
way of being myself.
You're welcome.
When you think about it.
Yes, honestly, I could
go on like this forever.
I could explain every
natural phenomenon.
The tides, the grass, the earth.
Oh no, is Maui a festival now?
I lived you.
I buried a judge.
You fell out of the tree.
Now you have coconuts.
What's the lesson here?
What's the most
important takeaway?
Here we go, this
is what Maui wins.
He's raking again.
And the tapestry
irritated my skin.
It's the map of my victories.
Look, Maui, now make sure
everything gets underway.
Look at this mean, mean Maui.
Just tapping,
singing, and clapping.
Throwing and snapping.
Oh, she's clapping.
Victory lap and
reintroducing the chorus.
All right, anyway, I want
to tell you: You're welcome.
What a wonderful
world, you know.
Hey, it's all good,
it's all good.
You're welcome.
Now that I think about
it, I have to go.
Hey, it's perfectly fine
to say "You're welcome".
Because I'm going to
need this trainer.
I'm sailing away,
further and further.
You're welcome.
Tomorrow we can do anything,
just not the people.
You're welcome.
And thank you very much.
Hey!
You lying, sneaky son of a...
Beach!
I'll smile at you later.
I'm going to leave the boat.
Ouch!
What?
Well, I'm hardly going to
go to Te Fiti with some kid.
I'm getting my hook.
My friend, you
already have yours.
I'm not Maui without it.
And if you keep going like this,
I have a cave for you to go into.
That's how I remember it.
Ouch!
She's fine. Look, she'll have
a whole island all to herself.
And she'll love it.
And I'll love you.
In my belly.
Oh, so close! I could watch that all
day. Enjoy the island. Maui, bye.
Hey, no, you have to
bring the heart back.
Hey!
A kid? No, I haven't seen her.
And she's back. Close your eyes.
I am Moana of...
Well done, me.
Was born, right, by, uh...
Restore the heart.
Uh...
I'll try my luck
with the monsters.
Okay, I'm out.
I thought we were friends.
Oh!
Wow!
What is wrong with you?
There's nothing wrong with me. I'm
great, haven't you heard that yet?
Are you..?
No.
No, no, no. Don't do that.
Scared.
No, no, no. Fear? Maui? No.
I don't know fear.
That's not a heart,
that's a curse.
And the moment I took it in my hand, I was
snatched from the sky and lost my hook.
Get rid of it!
Take that away.
Yes, that's enough.
I am a demigod.
And I will beat you.
You don't want anything
to happen to any of this.
Yes, exactly you.
Just the way you
don't want that.
This thing doesn't create
life, it's a beacon of death.
And if you don't get rid of
it, bad things will happen.
Get rid of what, please?
Yes.
The heart?
Don't do that.
Te Fiti!
The heart of Te Fiti?
If you look at the god like that,
you're going to get us killed.
I'm taking the two of us to Te
Fiti so you can put it back.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
You know, if I were wrong
even once, I'd be humble.
I promise.
What is that?
Kakamora.
Poisonous little scavengers.
They look kind of cute.
Define cute.
I wonder what they want here.
I don't know.
You can't sail.
I'm self-taught.
No magic hook, no magic power.
Give that back!
Maui, they took the heart!
We have to get it back!
Maui!
I told you, it's cursed!
There. Right there.
What are you doing?
Fleeing?
No, it's that way.
We'll never get it back.
Okay, I'll take care of it.
Hey, what am I supposed
to scare them with?
They're just going to kill you.
I'm going to need that hook.
We? By "we" you mean Mawe,
because we didn't do anything.
I did everything. By the way, Maui isn't
spelled with a "we", but with an "i".
We're alive.
But I'm still not
taking this thing back.
Why not?
Because to get to Te Fiti, you have
to go through Te Kā, the lava monster.
Have you ever fought a
lot of monsters, princess?
No. And you?
You want me to believe
that I'm your whole island?
Your boss
chose you.
"Chose" is a strong word.
I'm not going on a suicide
mission with just anyone.
To bring the heart
back, you need me.
I'm just...
I'm getting my hook.
End of discussion.
You'd be a hero again?
That's what you're after, right?
Well, girl, I am a hero.
Well, maybe you were.
But a lot has changed
in a thousand years.
Now you're the one who
stole Te Fiti's heart.
The guy who cursed
the whole world.
You're nobody's hero.
Ha ha! That's impossible.
I'm everyone's hero.
Oh, nice.
Just team up
against the demigod.
Look.
I promise.
If you bring it back,
you'll save the world.
You'd be everyone's hero.
Forever.
Sounds good, right?
Maui. Maui. Maui. Maui.
That is incredible.
Wow.
Look at the definition.
That's true.
If I do that, then you and your
people will worship me as a hero.
Act like one and maybe I will.
Deal.
You won't get rid of me.
You want a try?
I assume you're coming.
Okay.
To the lair of Tamatoa.
If anyone has my hook, it's
that stinging, grumpy rascal.
You can teach me how to sail.
That's not sailing, princess.
That's called wayfinding.
It's about knowing where
you're going in your mind.
It's about knowing where you
are and where you've been.
I'm not a princess.
I'm the chief's daughter.
It's exactly the same.
No.
Yes.
If you wear a dress and have an animal
sidekick, you're a princess, princess.
You're not a wayfinder.
Unless you find a way
to be less annoying.
Really?
Blowpipe dart in my butt cheek.
Whoever can speak
can also teach.
I'm a demigod.
Wayfinder.
Lesson one.
Go for it!
Loosen the tricycle.
No.
Not that.
The other one.
No.
We're measuring the stars.
We're not high-fiving the sky.
You feel the water.
It's warm.
That means we're
on the right track.
It's cold.
Wait a minute, it's
getting warmer.
Yuck!
That's disgusting!
What is wrong with you?
Huh?
Hahaha.
Moana!
Go!
Are you sure that
guy has your hook?
Tamatoa is not a guy.
He collects everything that's cool
and sinks to the bottom of the ocean.
Nothing is cooler than my hook.
Except maybe my face.
Or these muscles.
I'm getting my hook.
I don't see an entrance.
The entrance will only
appear after our offering.
I'm still falling.
This is madness.
The ocean chose
you for a reason.
Guess what.
I'm still falling.
I can do this.
How does my hair look?
Don't answer that.
You know what?
Maybe you can get back up and get out
of here while the Grumbos go to work.
Stop trying to get rid of me.
I can be helpful.
Yeah?
Like how, for example?
Example: When I just jumped into
that monster mouth and didn't die.
And I got you off that island.
Did no one else do that?
So what's our plan?
Oh, you're still there.
I was planning to do
this all by myself.
But today I'm not
having much luck.
Maui!
I could be useful if you let me.
Okay.
Really?
You know, sometimes
you're the hero in life.
And sometimes you're the pain.
Wait a minute, what?
Wow.
The shiny, glittering pain.
Sparkling.
What, are you
going to a funeral?
Do you know that I'm just
trying to motivate you?
You have to commit.
Say the other line I wrote.
Have fun with that.
Exactly.
Wow.
I'm a sparkling treasure.
Look here.
Do it again.
Oh, more convincing.
Sparkling.
Sideways.
Smarter.
Sparkling.
You're mangling the lines.
You sound like a drunk.
I don't even know what that was.
Sparkling.
Way too unpleasant.
Sparkling?
This is all crap.
I can't do this anymore.
Yes, you can.
You're the bait.
I'll just go up and get it.
Listen, if you go up
there, you're going to die.
At least then it would be over.
Okay, listen.
If you meet him, you
have to distract him.
And don't forget: He likes to
brag about how great he is.
Oh, you two seem
to get along well.
Not really.
Not anymore, since I
ripped his leg off.
You ripped his leg off..
Maui!
Wait a minute.
You're a human!
Oh!
What are you doing down here
in the realm of monsters?
Pick an eye, honey.
If I can't focus
on what I'm saying,
Yeah, pick one.
Just pick one.
You look weird.
But that necklace...
Don't!
Well, I ate my grandma.
And it took a week.
But she was absolutely huge.
Why are you here?
Because of you!
Because you're so fantastic!
I'm looking forward to
getting to know you!
Go ahead.
We mortals have
heard a lot about
the crab who ate his grandma
and became a legend!
Wait a minute.
Are you just trying
to provoke me?
To talk about myself?
Because if you...
I'd be happy to do that!
Huh?
Okay, guys, that's
exactly why we rehearse.
Lights!
Music!
Let's go!
Well, someone was or
hasn't always been so calm.
I was a trap, little crab, once
Now I know I can't be
as happy as an oyster.
Because I'm beautiful, baby.
Listen to your heart
Guys, you're the meanest
I need three words to
refute their arguments.
I'm a brother who shines
Not a single blemish
on the surface
Double check
One moment please.
Don't you know that?
Fish and dong, dong, dong
They chase after everything
Fish killer
I just love beautifully
plated food.
And you look like me too.
I'm back.
It's Maui time!
Yes!
Yes, I'm holding it right.
I know what I'm doing.
I didn't order calamari.
Well, then Maui must have
problems with his appearance.
Your little demigod.
What a terrible thought.
Get it?
You don't sing it
like you used to.
Yes, I have to give you credit for my
song and your tattoos on your skin.
Well, just like you and
me, we're saying goodbye.
I will never hide.
I can't.
I'm too shiny.
Watch me dance like a
diamond on the carpet.
I hit myself, but
don't be so shiny.
You're not bad to me, but
there will never be a dog.
My shelter was
moved further away.
You can keep trying.
Just don't come to me
and don't tell me why.
You can't take the
party with you.
You can die, die, die.
Now it's time to take it apart.
You ate me hard.
But from the one who left you,
it's human to chase the lever.
Don't make me feel desired.
You're trying to be tough.
But your arm just
isn't hard enough.
Oh yes.
You're shining so much.
And now it's time for
me to put you behind me.
I've never seen
anyone so radiant.
Let yourself into this love
that you will ever see.
There are a few more
than me, I'm so shiny.
Now I'll show you how
to clean your body.
Just for me.
No.
You'll never be
this shiny again.
You two look great and shiny.
Hey!
I have something shiny for you.
The heart of Te Fiti.
Don't give it to
him, little one.
You want it?
Come and get it.
You can't run away from me.
Okay, you keep surprising me.
The power of creation.
Where is it?
Let's go, Te Fiti.
Shall we?
And the heart?
Yes, I have it.
Now it belongs to me.
Wait a minute.
I understand.
She took a barnacle and covered it with
bioluminescent algae as a distraction.
There is no way out.
Oh, there is a way out.
Hey, did you like the song?
Comments or feedback?
Maui?
Listen, I really appreciate
what you did down there.
That takes courage.
Oh, now I understand.
A big, strong, handsome
guy is getting emotional.
And what do you do?
You laugh in his face.
Oh no.
Do I have something on my face?
Between my teeth?
Do I have something
between my teeth?
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
Shark head!
I like this part.
I mean, I mean the nice part.
I wasn't making fun
of the shark part.
Listen, my point is:
You did me a favor.
But you almost died.
And I couldn't even
defeat that stupid crap.
So the chances of beating
Te Kā are vanishingly small.
This mission has no chance.
Because you're still you
and I have a shark head.
Hey, it's all good, it's
all good, there's no wind.
We're going to die soon.
Because we're both going
to die on this boat.
Hey.
Maybe you try smiling.
Giant hook.
Maui is going to do
the dead man's float.
Hey!
Why are you acting like this?
Leave me alone.
You two.
How do you get your tattoos?
They just show up.
As soon as I heard them,
they just showed up.
How did you get this one?
That's the discovery
of Nunya by humans.
What is Nunya?
That's none of your business.
I'll just keep asking.
Let it be.
Why did that crab nudge me?
Leave it.
No!
I don't want to talk about it.
Give that back!
If you don't want to talk
that's fine.
But my island.
My people.
My family.
They won't survive
if we don't make it.
I want to help.
If you let me.
I wasn't born as a demigod.
I had human parents.
They decided they
didn't want me.
So they threw me into the sea.
As if I were nothing.
Somehow I was washed ashore.
Found by the gods.
They gave me my hook.
They made me Maui.
So I turned back to the people.
I gave them everything.
Islands.
Fire. Coconuts. I gave them
everything they ever wanted.
You took the heart for us.
You did everything for us.
So we love you.
Yes.
It was never enough.
You too were chosen
by the ocean.
That is the most
important realization.
Because it saw someone
who was worth saving.
And what am I now?
You are Maui.
The gods didn't make that true.
You did.
Not in front of the guest.
The wind.
Maui. He's back.
Sorry, chicken.
He knew no two voyages were alike,
each was different. A true wayfinder.
Consider all the water
as a bridge.
And not a barrier.
And if I were the ocean, I couldn't
find a better curly-haired,
loyal companion – no princess
– to resume my sea voyage with.
That's the nicest thing
you've ever said to me.
Should have saved
it for Te Fiti.
Yes, I did.
Moana..
You can do this.
You are Maui.
That's right.
It's Maui time.
Go and save the world.
Maui!
What are you doing?
We'll find a way in.
This is our chance.
Turn around.
No!
We won't make it.
Yes we will.
Moana, no!
I can do this!
Are you okay?
Maui?
I told you to turn back.
I thought we could make it.
We?
I thought I could make it.
I will find a way
to fix your hook.
The gods created my hook.
That cannot be fixed.
Next time I'll be more careful.
There is no next time.
But now we know that Te Ka
cannot follow us into the water.
We can find another way.
There is no other way.
I'm not going back.
Look at my hook.
One more blow and it's over.
But my people, my islands...
Without my hook I am nothing.
We are only here because you stole
the heart in the first place.
No.
We are here because the ocean
told you that you are special.
And you believed it.
I was born in Motonui.
Goodbye, Moana.
You will sail across the sea
and bring back the heart.
I'm not killing myself so you can prove
that you are something you're not.
The ocean chose me.
It chose us.
It made the wrong choice.
Goodbye, Moana.
Maui.
No, no.
Don't go.
Ocean, why did
you bring me here?
I was never the right person.
You should choose someone else.
You left the reef far behind.
Grandma.
I think I chose
the right path too.
I tried.
I was confident
that I could do it.
I can't do it.
If you are ready to go home,
I will accompany you.
Why are you hesitating?
I don't know.
I know a girl from an island.
She stands out from the crowd.
She loves the sea
and her people.
She makes her
whole family proud.
Sometimes the whole world
seems to be against you.
The journey might leave a scar.
But scars can heal and show
where you really stand.
The people you love
will change you.
What you have learned
will show you the way.
And nothing on earth
can be silenced.
The quiet voice inside you.
And when that voice
starts to whisper.
Moana, you've
already come so far.
Moana, listen.
Do you know who you are?
Who am I?
I am a girl who
loves her island.
And the girl who loves the sea.
It calls me.
I am the daughter of
the village chief.
We come from hunters
and gatherers.
Those who found their
way around the world.
They call me.
I got us out of our
current situation.
I burned, burned, burned.
I am everything I've
learned and much more.
And yet it calls to me.
And it's about knowing that.
I made it better.
It's inside me.
It's always fun
and entertaining.
I will carry you in my heart.
You will remind me of that.
I have a word for today.
I know the way.
I am finished now.
I am Moana of Motunui.
We have to lure Te Kā
away and slip past.
Because he cannot follow
us through the water.
You don't understand any of
this because you're a coward.
Okay, Te Ka.
Try and catch me.
You came back.
I should never have left.
Use your hook.
One more blow.
Here, you have to
catch me first.
Maui. Thanks. You're welcome.
Let's go.
Moana!
Oh no.
Te Fiti?
She is gone.
Te Ka!
Who you really are.
Te Fiti.
Your hook.
With or without a hook.
I'm still Maui.
Hey. Hey.
Te Fiti.
How are you?
Me Maui.
We met back then...
I think what he's
trying to say...
What I did was wrong.
And I obviously have a lot of
things I still need to resolve.
From my past.
Issues and things like that.
I am just a humble demigod
trying to find this..
That is no excuse.
I'm sorry.
Really.
Go ahead. It would be rude to
refuse a gift from a goddess.
Who am I?
Right now I am
grateful. Thank you.
I'll miss you, Drumstick.
You know, Motonui is that way.
You should come
visit me sometime.
I'd love to.
We would love to
have you with us.
Anytime.
Besides, my people could
use a master wayfinder.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Moana.
I might have gone
out a little too far.
I'm so proud of you.
Flowers